Hey Fox, which health
insurance plans are available to us in 2025?
In today's video, we will know this.
Fox, health insurance is
very important for a middle class person because
hospital expenses are touching the sky and
a single hospitalization is far away for the middle class to
come below the poverty line.
Purchasing a health insurance policy is
very easy but it is difficult to
purchase the best health insurance policy. Now the
question arises that
what is the definition of the best health insurance policy,
my definition is completely different and the
insurance company which settles your claim hassle free is the
best health insurance policy in my view.
Now purchasing a health insurance
policy is not easy. First of all, the
question arises that which
health insurance policy of which company should I
purchase? Should I just see what are the
features of the health insurance policy and
purchase a health insurance policy after analyzing the features or should I
check the claim settlement ratio of the insurance company or should I check
which is the cheapest insurance? In today's
video, I will present before you  I have brought a
comparison of four health insurance plans
and these four health insurance plans are the
health insurance plans which are the
most famous today, they are a revolution and their
features are unique, so please watch this video
till the end and share it with your friends and relatives, if you are visiting
Insurance Seva for the first
time then subscribe to Insurance Seva now
and press the bell icon as well.
[Music]
In today's video I will talk to you
about Optima Secure of ADFC Aer Go,
Elevate Plan of IC Lombard,
Super Star Plan which has been
launched by Star Health and recently in 2025
Care Health Insurance has launched its Ultimate
Care Plan.
We will check the fundamentals of all the four health insurance plans, we will
check what are their USPs and
features, are these plans better than each other,
so first of all let's talk as always about the
fundamentals of the insurance company,
here I will talk about the Cured Claim
Ratio, you are seeing the Claim Settlement Ratio,
I have blanked it because
whatever data of Claim Settlement Ratio is available in the
market  The data available is
not authentic because IDA does
not publish the claim settlement ratio.
IDA only publishes the in-curred claim ratio. So,
I do not trust any data that is not certified. So,
here we will talk about the
in-curred claim ratio of SDAC Arg, which is at 81, which is
very good. ICS Lombard is at 79,
Star Health is at 66 and Care Health
Insurance is at 50.8 as per the Annual Report
of IRDA
2024. If I talk about in-curred claim ratio, it is
considered best. It should be above 65
and also less than 80. So here
SDAC Arg and ICICI Lombard are up to the
mark. The best health insurance companies will be
considered. Solvency ratio means
how much money you have against your liability.
Regulatory says it is 1.5, so that of
SDAC Arg is 1.68, which means they have
₹1000000
against this if we
talk about AC to Lombard then they have 2.62 that means against a
liability of ₹1 they have
₹62 available this is excellent if we
talk about Star Health then they have against a
liability of ₹2000000 that
means their solvency ratio will be 2.21 and on the other hand
Care Health Insurance will have 1.74
and now we will talk about network
hospitals i.e.
which hospitals are available in these companies for cashless
so ADAC Rugo has 14000 plus
ICC Lombard has 15000 plus
and on the other hand Star Health has
14000 plus network hospitals
but Care Health Insurance is at the forefront
they have 28000 plus network
hospitals according to their website claim
process reimbursement claim process
because health  Insurance only means a
claim. You are purchasing health insurance
so that if tomorrow you have to make a
claim, you get it. The
Reimers Plan claim process will be online here. If you
send all the documents to HDFC Care@hdfcergo.com,
your claim will be settled. Same is the case with
ICC Lombard. If
you upload all the documents on the Care app, then your
claim gets settled. Talking about Star Health,
their claim settlement is a bit
typical, it is offline. You have to submit all the documents
in their branch and
then your claim is settled. But the
claim settlement of Care Health Insurance is also
fully online. By going to their app and clicking on
their link, you
can process your claim and submit the claim documents, then
your claim gets settled.
In this slide, we will talk about the
USP of these plans, what is
unique, what special
features are provided in these plans. I will talk about SDF Surgo
first, so Optima  Secure plan was
launched in 2021. It has been almost 4 years since
this plan was launched but the
features of this plan are still 4 years old.
Nothing has been updated in it but the
insurance company had added Global and
Global Plus variants in it a year ago
and this year they have added Optimus Secure Lite
in it but the features are the same.
Secure benefit is 2x coverage
from day one i.e. buy one get one free.
In a policy of Rs 10 lakh, you
get a cover of Rs 20 lakh from the very first day. Plus benefit is
here, it will increase annually at Rs 50.
Your cover will
go up to a maximum of 100% even if there is a claim or not.
Protect benefit is inside it. From day one,
you get cover for the entire list of consumer bills. It will be an in-
build cover, there is no add-on cover.
Restoration is 100% in-build in it.
% additional premium given. Unlimited
restoration. Unlimited restoration. Same
person, same illness.  It gets added for this.
If I talk against this, then
IIC Lombard has Power Booster.
Power Booster means that your 100% time cover will
increase every year. There will be no maximum limit. There will be
lifetime increase and it will
beat your inflation also. This is an add-on feature
and the same feature is also there in your Superstar,
which we call Superstar Bonus and
Ultimate
Care Health Insurance has brought the same feature which is
called Infinity Bonus. This feature is very good
because this feature will beat your inflation.
Next is the
USP of Infinity Board. You
can take unlimited claim once in your lifetime.
With the add-on cover, if you get unlimited
claim in this, then you can avail it.
You can take unlimited claim once in your lifetime. The
same feature is available
in Superstar, which is called
Limitless Cover. It will be optional but this feature will
not be available in Ultimate Care. There is
a unique feature here that Grace
You will also receive a claim during the grace period of 30 days.
Until now, claims were not received
during that period, but in this plan,
you will receive a claim during the grace period.
Durable equipment cover is available
in two plans: IC Lombard's Elevate
plan with an add-on and Star Health's
Superstar with an add-on. This
option will not be available in Care. Claim Protector, that is, the
same protect benefit that you have
in ADFC Air Go. ACC Lombard also has a
Claim Protector add-on. Star
Health's Superstar will have a consumer cover turned on,
and if you opt for Claim Shield in Care Health's Ultimate Care,
then
all four of your consumer items will be covered.
Talking about the next features,
here comes the add-on cover for critical illness and
personal accident. You can avail add-on cover from IC
Lombard, but
if we talk about Star Health's Superstar plan,
you will get an early renewal discount of 2.5% if
you renew your policy 30 days in advance.  This
discount increases in your Ultimate Care plan.
If you renew before 30 days, you get a
discount of 5%. If
you renew your policy within 30 days,
you will get a discount of 2.5%.
Long term discount is
available in all four policies. However,
if I talk about ICICI Lombard's Elevate plan and
Optima Secure or
SDFC Ergo, there is only a 3-year
policy option in which you
get a discount. However, in Superstar
and Ultimate Care, you can take a 5-year policy
together, where you will get a
discount. Also, if I talk about
Ultimate Care, there is a
welcome discount available in which
you get 30% on taking a 3-year policy
in the first year,
20% in the second year, and 10% in the third year. The
next
slide says that the
Superstar plan offers premium waiver benefit. Here, if the
proposer, who should also be the insured,
dies due to a critical illness,
Due to accidental death, 1 year
's premium is waived. But
if I talk against this, then
there is a multiplier new benefit in the Care Ultimate Care plan.
If you are taking a policy of 3 years or 5 years together, then
you are getting a discount. You will get it
from day one even after skipping three or five years.
If you are paying a premium for 5 years in a policy of Rs 10 lakh, then the
first claim itself can be
of Rs 50 lakh. This is a very good feature that
Future Shield is offering,
which means that whichever spouse you have will be added immediately after
marriage. If you
take Future Shield as an add-on, then if
I talk against this, if I talk about
Ultimate Care, then there is a
premium payback option. If you
remain claim free for 5 years and do not make any claim, then
your first year's premium
is returned to you. This will keep happening after every 5 years.
Loyalty boost is also given
if your Ultimate Care
remains claim free for 7 years.  Your policy
doubles your base cover. This is going to be
completely separate from the cumet bonus and your limitless cover.
OPD cover means
you are given OPD vouchers for four
general physicians and four super specialties
with a maximum limit of ₹5000000.
You will get 100% cleaning but you will have to
take it on a cashless basis only. You
can get dental cleaning done and dental
checkup done. There is another special feature in
Superstar which is Freeze Your Age
entry, your age will be locked.
Your
premium will not increase until you make a claim but will
increase as per inflation.
This benefit will remain till 55 years.
Your age will be unlocked when you turn 56. This feature is
in your Superstar plan.
In comparison to all the four plans,
this feature will be available in this plan only. Nowadays,
cover for many diseases is being given to you from 31 days
and there are many policies which are going to
give it from day one as well. If I talk about
ICC  Under Lombard's Elevate plan,
you can take Jump Start. If
you have diabetes, hypertension,
hyperlipidemia, obesity, you will get cover for it from 31 days. By
paying a little additional premium, you will get the same cover.
Under Star's Superstar plan, here
you will get cover for diabetes, hypertension, hyperlipidemia, and
PTCA done prior to one year, that is,
you will get cover for these diseases from 31 days.
If you have taken this add-on cover, then there is
also instant cover in Care's Ultimate Care.
Here
they have added one more disease, hypothyroidism, and
coronary artery disease. You will get cover for these diseases
from 31 days if any one of these
diseases is available to you. Now we will talk
about the basic features of these plans, that is,
what are the normal features. So first of all, there are
sum assured options. Options of Rs 5 lakh, 10
lakh, 15 lakh, 20 lakh, 25 lakh, 50 lakh and Rs 1 crore are available in
Optima Secure. There is
also an option of Rs 3 crore, but that is for Global and
Global Plus.  ICICI
Lombard has options ranging from ₹5 lakh to ₹3 crore. There
is another option here,
unlimited time cover. Unlimited time cover
is available in only a few policies but it is a very
good feature. If you feel that you do not have to
compromise on time cover, or if
you feel that
you should get everything when you go to the hospital, then opt for
unlimited time cover. You will have to
pay a little more premium but you will be
tension free. This option is
available to you. Under Star's Super Star
plan, there is a minimum cover of ₹10 lakh
and you will get a maximum unlimited cover.
Talking about care,
options ranging from ₹5 lakh to a maximum of ₹1 crore will be available under Ultimate Care.
Talking about entry, there is
no limit in all four policies. The
minimum age for any type of entry is 18 years,
but a person of any age can
purchase the policy. However, under Star Health's
Superstar plan,
you get unlimited cover above 65 years of age.  And you will not get a sum of ₹ crore
Policy tenure: 1 year, 2 years, 3
years policy options are available
but
you can purchase a 5 year policy in Star's Superstar and Ultimate Care. If we
talk about variants, Global
Global Plus is available in Optima Secure.
Also, you have the option of Lite in Optima Secure.
If you want a slightly lower premium, it will be
available. There are
no variants in the remaining three plans. A simple
plan is available: Family Size: Two Adults,
Four Kids, Optima Secure: Two Adults, Three
Kids, IC Lowada Elevate Plan: Two Adults,
Four Kids, Your Superstar Plan and Two Adults,
Two Kids, Care's Ultimate Care Plan There is
no capping on room rent in all the four plans but you will
get an inbuilt single private AC room in the Elevate plan. The room
modified slide shows that there is no
capping on ICU/ICCU in all the four policies. There will be
no payment for pre and
post hospitalization. This is a very important
point.
60 days and 180 days for any health insurance policy  There is a standard of 90 days
in Optima Secure but ICC
Lombard went a little ahead, they made it 90 days
and 180 days and the same
in your Star Superstar but it has come
down a little in Ultimate Care plan, it will be
60 and 90 days only, in this
your pre and post hospitalization,
day care treatment, modern treatment up to
time, no capping, no sub limit has been kept,
talking about e-consultation, here
e-consultation for critical illness can be taken
in HDFC R Go Optimum Secure
but tele-consultation will
be unlimited, in ICC Lombard's Elevate plan it will be
available with add-on cover, it is not available in Star Superstar, you will have unlimited
consultation for physicians in
Ultimate Care plan, now let
us start the next slide in which
comes restoration unlimited in all four
plans for the same person, same illness,
in ICICI Lombard for the same person, same
illness, you will have to keep a gap of 40 days,
here for road ambulance  We are talking about
up to sum covered. There is
no capping limit in all the four policies. If we
talk about air ambulance, it
is inbuilt here.
In Optima Secure, hospitalization up to ₹ lakh will be available
with add-on cover. In ICICI Lombard,
hospitalization up to ₹ 5 lakh will be
inbuilt in Star Health's Superstar, but
with add-on cover, you will have to take it in Ultimate's year. The
no claim bonus which
I am talking about is unbuilt, then it will go up to 100% annually on 50
Plus benefit. If we
talk about Optima Secure Elevate, then the
yearly maximum will go up to 100% on 20. It will
not be reduced in case of a claim. The
yearly maximum at 50 will be 100% in Superstar. And the
same is in your care health insurance, which will
not be reduced. Home care domicile
treatment up to sum is covered in all the four policies.
PD means pre-agistration
period is inbuilt for 36 months. In some policies, that is, if I
talk about Ultimate Care, then you can avail it
there.  You can reduce
annual health checkup by paying additional premium.
In-built ADFC Aer Go Optima Secure
₹5000000
maximum limit ₹15000 can be availed with ICC Lombard add-on.
In Superstar, you can avail 1 per
sum cover maximum ₹255000 with add-on and
along with this, you will get
alternative treatment up to Rs.50000 in Care Health Insurance. All the
treatments including Unani Siddha are covered as alternatives in all the
four policies. Maternity cover is
available in only two plans.
With ICC Lombard add-on, you will get 10 per sum cover maximum
₹1 lakh maternity cover
with a waiting period of 2 years. But
in Star's Superstar, you will get option 1 and option 2.
You will get delivery of ₹50000 and ₹1 lakh in option A
with a waiting period of 2 years and
delivery of ₹0000 in option B with a waiting period of 1 year.
Consumer bill
items are inbuilt.  You will have to take an add-on for your ADFC plan
in Optima Secure and the other three plans.
For that, the
wellness program is not available in ADFC.
You will get an add-on for up to 30, with an S Lord add-on for
20, Superstar for 20 and your
Ultimate Care for 30. Deductible
options are available.
Choose a deductible of ₹25,000, 50,000, and ₹1 lakh under ADFC plans.
Your premium will be reduced. The co-
payment option is optional in ICC Lord,
but if we talk about Superstar, then the
deductible option is available here, which is
available up to ₹1 lakh, but
you will not get a deductible in Ultimate Care. Now the
time has come to complete this video. As
always, like every video, I will complete this
video with the premium of all these four insurance plans.
You should check that you have seen the fundamentals of these four plans,
you have seen the features, you have seen the
special features. Now
what do you say about the premium? According to me, the premium
is the most important because the budget  First of all I have to see
which plan suits my budget.
First of all ADAC Ergo Optima Secure is ₹1
lakh, except for 40 years, Delhi
NCR premium will be
9787 in which everything is inbuilt, there are
no optional things, in this I have added power booster in IC Lord, I have
added refine, room
modification
₹2500000
[Music]
72 After adding almost all the add-ons,
if we talk about the premium then ICICI
Lombard is number one here, it will be economical among these four.
Now you check
which plan suits you as per your need.
My advice would be that you just
check the fundamentals of the insurance company
and if we talk about fundamentals then
SDFC RG and ICICI Lombard
both will be the best plans. If you have
any queries related to these four health insurance plans, you
can ask me in my comment
box. I will meet you in my next
video, till then Jai Hind Jai Bharat.